<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Customer Stories - Digits</title><description>Top startup founders use Digits to automate their accounting. Here are their stories about simplifying finances &amp; getting financial clarity.</description><link>https://digits.com/</link><language>en</language><item><title>Mana Accounting &amp; Advisory: Saving Hours with AI-Powered Accounting</title><link>https://digits.com/customers/mana-accounting-advisory-saving-hours-with-ai-powered-accounting/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://digits.com/customers/mana-accounting-advisory-saving-hours-with-ai-powered-accounting/</guid><description>By adopting Digits, Mana Accounting &amp; Advisory eliminated tedious manual tasks, streamlined client onboarding, and gained the freedom to deliver deeper insights and advisory services.</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mana.cpa/&quot;&gt;Mana Accounting &amp;amp; Advisory&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to serving startups and law firms by acting as their in-house finance team. From bookkeeping and payroll to bill pay and tax, the firm takes a holistic approach to client finances—always with the goal of delivering actionable insights, not just numbers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Challenge 🧮&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Mana grew, the tools couldn’t keep pace. QuickBooks and Zoho handled the basics, but left the team buried in manual work:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating and managing transaction rules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Categorizing line items one by one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cleaning up messy historical data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reporting was another pain point. Clients wanted clear takeaways–what to do with the numbers  –not just templated spreadsheets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founder and CEO &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/joshuachapel/&quot;&gt;Josh Chapel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; summed it up:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A lot of the work wasn’t difficult—it was just time-consuming. Manual categorizations, cleanups, and boilerplate reporting slowed us down. Our clients wanted to know what to do next with their numbers, and we didn’t have the right tools to deliver that efficiently.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onboarding new clients often came with another layer of added friction. Each setup meant chasing credentials, hand-holding through every step, and wasting valuable time before any real work could begin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Digits? 🚀&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an early believer in AI’s potential, Josh had been following Digits long before it became available to accounting firms. When it did, it felt like a perfect match—Digits aligned seamlessly with Mana’s philosophy of continuous improvement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Josh wasn’t struggling with complex work—he was stuck in time-consuming, repetitive tasks. Cleanups dragged on. Categorization required constant manual input. Onboarding new clients slowed everything down. And clients wanted better answers, faster.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digits delivered.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cleanups that took hours now take minutes. Transactions come in already categorized, no rule-building required. Clients connect their accounts without hand-holding, and reporting finally looks and feels as sharp as the insights inside it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, Digits gave Josh and his team the freedom to focus on what really matters: delivering value through insight and advisory—not getting buried in busywork.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a firm built on doing things better every day, Digits wasn’t just a tool. It was a turning point.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“With Digits, categorizations are already built in—it’s just a matter of glancing through. That’s serious time savings for us and for our clients.” – Josh Chapel&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact and Results 💅&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digits quickly became a time-saver and confidence booster for Mana’s small but growing team.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Efficiency Gains:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cleanups that used to take entire afternoons now take minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PDF bank statements are uploaded directly into Digits for instant processing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accurate AI-driven categorization out of the box. No rule-building required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saves up to five hours per client project, freeing Mana’s team for higher-value work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy Adoption:&lt;/strong&gt;  With only three team members, simplicity was key. Digits delivered.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Staff described the platform as &lt;strong&gt;intuitive, modern, and far less intimidating&lt;/strong&gt; than legacy tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minimal training was needed&lt;/strong&gt;—the team quickly gained confidence and consistency across clients&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Better Client Experience:&lt;/strong&gt; Client onboarding is now fast and friction-free. With just an invitation and a few clicks, new clients connect their accounts without needing extra guidance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No more credential-chasing or setup delays&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clients receive beautiful, interactive dashboards with smart charts and widgets—now &lt;strong&gt;enhanced by Digits’&lt;/strong&gt; AI-driven automation for even faster insights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, Digits has freed Mana’s accountants to focus more on &lt;strong&gt;insights and advisory&lt;/strong&gt;—the work that truly drives client value&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Digits gives us more time to focus on conversations and insights instead of just getting accurate numbers. That’s the future of accounting.” – Josh Chapel&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking Ahead 🌟&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Josh sees AI as the driving force reshaping the profession. He believes tools like Digits will reduce tedious manual work, pushing accountants toward higher-value analysis and strategy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Mana, that means expanding advisory services—even for base clients—by providing deeper insights alongside accurate numbers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Digits shows you where the future of accounting is going. If you want your firm to grow, get involved sooner rather than later.” – Josh Chapel&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ready to save hours and elevate your client experience? &lt;a href=&quot;https://digits.com/demo/&quot;&gt;Book a demo with Digits today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Olive Knits – Empowering Creative Confidence with Clear Finances through Digits</title><link>https://digits.com/customers/olive-knits-empowering-creative-confidence-with-clear-finances-through-digits/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://digits.com/customers/olive-knits-empowering-creative-confidence-with-clear-finances-through-digits/</guid><description>Discover how Olive Knits, founded by entrepreneur and knitwear designer Marie Greene, found freedom from financial stress with Digits. By automating bookkeeping and gaining real-time visibility, Olive Knits replaced sleepless nights with clarity, confidence, and the ability to scale.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oliveknits.com/&quot;&gt;Olive Knits&lt;/a&gt; is a thriving creative small business that empowers knitters with patterns, workshops, and a supportive community called &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://oliveknits.thinkific.com/memberships/knit-camp&quot;&gt;Knit Camp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Founded by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oliveknits.com/about/&quot;&gt;Marie Greene&lt;/a&gt;, a passionate entrepreneur, the company’s mission is to help knitters gain creative confidence while fostering connection. Through a blend of educational resources and community building, Olive Knits has become a trusted resource for makers worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, behind the vibrant community and steady growth, Marie found herself facing a frustrating—yet all too common—challenge: managing the finances of a small business.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Financial Struggle 🧵&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many entrepreneurs, Marie initially relied on a patchwork of accounting solutions. QuickBooks felt overwhelming. Spreadsheets became unmanageable. Other tools never adapted to her corrections, forcing her to repeat the same work and leaving her unable to trust the results. Even with a private bookkeeper, she found herself needing to dedicate hours each week answering calls, emails, and clarifying transactions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result? Stress, backlogs, and sleepless nights.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I used to stay awake worrying about the state of my books,” Marie recalled. “Even with a bookkeeper, I felt like I was still doing too much of the work myself.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discovering Digits 🔍&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One late night, in the middle of insomnia brought on by accounting stress, Marie turned to ChatGPT for help. She searched for AI bookkeeping solutions and discovered Digits on a list of top platforms. Intrigued by its promise of automation and clarity, she decided to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her goal was simple: eliminate the time sink and stress of bookkeeping while gaining reliable, and timely visibility into her finances.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Digits Impact 🎯&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since adopting Digits, Olive Knits has experienced dramatic improvements in financial management:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clear Financial Visibility Anytime&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Digits’ real-time clarity eliminated the backlogs and negative surprises.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Now I can instantly pull up what I need — whether it’s downloading a statement or checking a category. That visibility is priceless.” - Marie&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significant Cost &amp;amp; Time Savings&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
By replacing her previous bookkeeping setup, Marie saved about &lt;strong&gt;70% in monthly costs&lt;/strong&gt; and at least &lt;strong&gt;three hours per week&lt;/strong&gt;. With transactions connected automatically and automated categorization learning the nuances of her business quickly, manual uploads and back-and-forths are no longer necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intuitive AI-Driven Categorization&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Digits’ categorization became a standout feature. “It just learns,” Marie emphasized. “Instead of re-explaining the same transaction every month, Digits recognizes it and saves me time. It’s like having a bookkeeper who actually remembers.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setting the Stage for Growth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
With financial clarity, Marie now feels prepared for future business milestones — like bringing in a business partner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Digits makes my business decisions so much easier because I can see the full financial picture instantly,” - Marie&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Digits Stands Out ✨&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of juggling the complexity of QuickBooks or the ongoing demands of a private bookkeeper, Marie found Digits. It pairs automation with intelligence, giving her confidence that everything is handled—and the freedom to focus on what matters most.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I recommend Digits to any entrepreneur who wants time savings, cost savings, and reliable clarity. Especially if you have multiple income streams, Digits is a game-changer.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ready to Knit Together Financial Clarity?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digits is helping small business owners like Marie trade late-night stress for peace of mind and growth opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is your business ready to experience streamlined accounting with Digits? &lt;a href=&quot;https://digits.com/&quot;&gt;Sign up today.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Freeplay&apos;s Financial Transformation with Digits</title><link>https://digits.com/customers/freeplay/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://digits.com/customers/freeplay/</guid><description>Discover how Freeplay, an innovative seed-stage AI startup, transformed their financial operations by partnering with Digits. By replacing fragmented systems with Digits&apos; integrated solution, Freeplay cut costs by 50%, streamlined processes, and refocused on their core mission of creating exceptional AI products.</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 13:39:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://freeplay.ai/&quot;&gt;Freeplay&lt;/a&gt;, an innovative seed-stage AI startup, is on a mission to empower product teams in creating exceptional AI products. By providing tools for prompt engineering, observability, testing, and evaluation, Freeplay helps teams build the data flywheel they need to constantly improve quality. However, as a growing startup, Freeplay faced significant challenges in managing its financial operations efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Challenge 🧮&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before partnering with Digits, Freeplay relied on a combination of another accounting application for software and a mid-sized fractional consulting firm for accounting and CFO services. This setup led to disjointed operations, finger-pointing between software and service providers when things didn’t go right, and unexpected surges in their monthly costs. &lt;a href=&quot;https://freeplay.ai/&quot;&gt;Ian Cairns&lt;/a&gt;, co-founder of Freeplay, found himself entangled in resolving discrepancies rather than focusing on growth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The software and service were supposed to work harmoniously, but in practice, they were often blaming one another leading to unnecessary billable hours and complexity for me as a founder.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Discovering Digits 🚀&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freeplay&apos;s transition to Digits was driven by the desire for an integrated and streamlined financial solution. Ian Cairns was introduced to Digits through Jeff, a former colleague at Twitter. Convinced by the potential of having both technology and human expertise in one place, Ian decided to give Digits a try.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s what set Digits apart for Freeplay:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unified Accountability&lt;/strong&gt;: Digits offered a seamless integration of technology with human oversight, aligning incentives and eliminating the blame game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost Efficiency&lt;/strong&gt;: By transitioning to Digits, Freeplay cut its monthly accounting bill by &amp;gt;50%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Human Support&lt;/strong&gt;: With dedicated financial experts, Ian experienced reassurance and reduced mental overhead, allowing him to focus on core business activities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Transformation 💅&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digits&apos; impact on Freeplay was tangible:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time Savings&lt;/strong&gt;: Enhanced efficiency meant less time spent on financial tasks, freeing Ian for product development and sales.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simplicity&lt;/strong&gt;: The integrated services streamlined operations, reducing complexities and stress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Efficiency and Clarity&lt;/strong&gt;: With Digits providing integrated financial management, Freeplay experienced a seamless alignment of accounting, FP&amp;amp;A, and tax services. This consolidation eliminated the complexities of dealing with multiple vendors, resulting in faster decision-making and reduced mental overhead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The biggest benefit has been the decrease in time spent thinking about accounting. As much as I don’t notice what’s going on with Digits, that’s a good thing in my world. The stress and worry are way down. The time spent is also meaningfully down.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digits not only optimized Freeplay’s financial management but also strengthened its operational efficiency. By aligning with Freeplay’s innovative ethos, Digits has become a reliable partner, providing clarity and peace of mind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The stress and complexity are reduced, allowing us to focus on helping our customers build incredible AI products. I highly recommend Digits to any startup looking to simplify financial management.&amp;quot; Ian Cairns.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ready to elevate your financial operations? &lt;a href=&quot;https://digits.com/demo&quot;&gt;Book a demo with Digits today&lt;/a&gt; and discover how you can transform your financial management like Freeplay.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Unlocking Effortless Financial Management: Spearus</title><link>https://digits.com/customers/spearus/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://digits.com/customers/spearus/</guid><description>Discover how Spearus, a forward-thinking IT consulting and reselling firm, transformed their financial operations by adopting Digits, leaving behind the frustrations of traditional accounting tools.
</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 14:23:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;The Challenge 🎯&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spearus.com/&quot;&gt;Spearus&lt;/a&gt;, led by CEO &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/robertbanchero&quot;&gt;Robert Banchero&lt;/a&gt;, partners with industry giants like Dell and VMware to deliver cutting-edge IT solutions. However, managing financial operations was a hurdle. Traditional tools like QuickBooks proved cumbersome and required deep accounting knowledge, making simple tasks unnecessarily complex.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;QuickBooks was clunky and required accounting expertise. It was a constant battle just to perform basic functions,&amp;quot; Robert shared.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a disappointing experience with Puzzle, which presented modern analytics but fell short on functionality and affordability, Spearus sought a solution that truly matched their needs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Digits Solution 🚀&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduced to Digits by a college friend, Robert found the platform’s seamless, intuitive design to be a game-changer for Spearus. Digits offered a refreshing ease that other software lacked.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Immediate Benefits 🌟&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revitalized Engagement:&lt;/strong&gt; Digits rekindled Robert&apos;s interest in managing the business’ finances—transforming accounting from a chore to an enjoyable task.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Streamlined Usability:&lt;/strong&gt; With intuitive categorization and a user-friendly interface, Digits eliminated the complexity of previously daunting tasks. The team at Spearus could easily adjust entries, ensuring accuracy and efficiency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Insightful Analytics:&lt;/strong&gt; The analytics dashboard provided valuable insights, enabling Spearus to monitor their financial health with ease and make informed decisions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time and Cost Efficiency:&lt;/strong&gt; Spearus anticipates significant savings in both time and costs, reducing reliance on otherwise costly accounting service fees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Transformation 🔄&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spearus is a testament to the transformative power of intuitive financial software. With Digits, Robert is ready to present organized financial records to his accountant, promising a seamless tax season. Digits&apos; ease of use and robust features support ongoing growth, making it an integral part of Spearus&apos; strategy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I&apos;ve enjoyed working with Digits. It&apos;s not just about saving time; it’s about empowering me to manage finances with confidence. I wholeheartedly recommend Digits to anyone looking to simplify their financial operations,&amp;quot; says Robert.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experience the Digits difference. &lt;a href=&quot;https://my.digits.com/join&quot;&gt;Start your free trial today&lt;/a&gt; and discover how seamless financial management can fuel your growth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Abra’s Financial Transformation with Digits</title><link>https://digits.com/customers/abra/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://digits.com/customers/abra/</guid><description>Discover how Abra revolutionized its financial management with Digits, transforming manual processes into efficient, AI-driven automation. </description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 16:42:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.helloabra.com/&quot;&gt;Abra&lt;/a&gt;, a pioneering Agentic AI Meeting Orchestration platform, helps Procurement teams skip meetings while staying aligned and in control of vendor relationships.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Abra expands, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/byron-revels/&quot;&gt;Byron Revels&lt;/a&gt;, the co-founder and CEO, along with his team actively explore AI tools to optimize their operations and avoid increasing unnecessary headcount. This proactive practice is what led them to discover Digits, and ultimately transforming their financial management process and experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, Abra relied heavily on QuickBooks and manual Excel processes for financial modeling. The company&apos;s team, including Byron, spent excessive time updating categorizations and producing financial statements for investors which was cumbersome and prone to errors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I was spending a ton of time trying to keep our financial model accurate and up-to-date.&amp;quot; Byron noted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The need for an automated solution that could ensure accuracy and provide real-time insights into their runway and overall financial health was clear.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why Digits?&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abra discovered Digits while seeking AI solutions to streamline operations. Digits was chosen for its ability to:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI-Driven Automation&lt;/strong&gt;: Seamlessly automate bookkeeping, eliminating tedious manual processes and reducing errors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Streamlined Financial Oversight:&lt;/strong&gt; Effortlessly handle complex financial tasks, providing real-time insights and accuracy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced Efficiency:&lt;/strong&gt; A user-friendly interface allowing easy categorization, saving time on financial modelling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After implementation, Abra experienced additional benefits, including responsive customer service, which led to immediate integration of their feedback into the product. This experience cemented their decision that Digits was a far superior accounting platform, perfectly suited to meet the needs of their rapidly growing business.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The swift response to our feedback on runway calculations was impressive, making us feel truly heard and valued as users!&amp;quot; Byron shared.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Results and Impact&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digits’ adoption led to significant improvements for Abra:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced Financial Clarity:&lt;/strong&gt; With AI-driven categorization, Abra gained reliable insights without labor-intensive manual checks. Byron described the process as, &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;A relief from the anxiety of double-checking mismatched numbers.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operational Efficiency&lt;/strong&gt;: With Digits, Abra streamlined bookkeeping processes, saving almost 2 hours per week—totalling a full day reclaimed each month. This efficiency has enabled the team to spend more time focusing on strategic growth rather than back-office tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reduced Error Margin:&lt;/strong&gt; Automated updates in categorizations, like contractor classifications, significantly reduced error margins and improved trust in the system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Complete Transition:&lt;/strong&gt; Abra has fully transitioned from QuickBooks Online to Digits, resulting in cost savings, a simplified technology stack, and a far more enjoyable accounting experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Future with Digits&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abra plans to continue leveraging Digits for quarterly reports and explore additional services such as tax preparation. They look forward to planned innovations like prompt-based AI assistants and tools, promising to further enhance their financial management. As Abra scales, Digits remains a crucial ally, providing the agility and precision needed to keep pace with their growth, setting a benchmark for innovative financial solutions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Financial Insights Unlocked: How Partiful Elevated Their Accounting Process with Digits</title><link>https://digits.com/customers/partiful/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://digits.com/customers/partiful/</guid><description>Discover how Partiful revolutionized their financial management by adopting Digits – transforming outdated processes into real-time, AI-driven insights, unlocking seamless efficiency and enabling further focus on their core mission.</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 10:11:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://partiful.com/&quot;&gt;Partiful&lt;/a&gt;, a cutting-edge social events platform, aims to redefine how people gather by enabling seamless and meaningful connections. Before teaming up with Digits, their financial management felt like piecing together a puzzle with outdated tools and tedious spreadsheets – ultimately distracting them from driving their core mission forward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relying on a traditional approach to accounting, Partiful had an external firm doing all the accounting in Quickbooks and their FP&amp;amp;A work out of spreadsheets. Ultimately, every month, the team would receive a cumbersome package of Excel spreadsheets and difficult-to-digest reports.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;We were spending unnecessary time just trying to understand our spend, digging through spreadsheets to trace spikes or changes back to their source.&amp;quot; remarked &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/jessica-eames-41029ba0/&quot;&gt;Jess Eames&lt;/a&gt;, Head of Business and Product Operations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This disjointed approach consumed valuable time and resources, with lengthy email threads and inefficient communication only adding to the complexity. This ultimately made it more challenging for the team to quickly derive actionable insights from their financial data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why Digits?&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transition to Digits was sparked by a serendipitous meeting between Partiful’s team and Digits’ founder. Excited by the prospect of a streamlined, AI-driven platform at a fraction of their previous costs, Partiful dove in!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Product-First Efficiency:&lt;/strong&gt; With intuitive UX and clean interface, Digits enabled Partiful to easily navigate financial data, understand at a high level what was happening, and allow them to dig deep into the transactional details. Jess appreciated, &amp;quot;The product-first flow was incredibly efficient for someone without a finance background.&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-Service Capabilities&lt;/strong&gt;: With Digits, previous manual requests for spreadsheets became quick, on-demand access to reports and financial information. The self-serve features allowed Partiful to tailor financial views as needed, dramatically reducing delays and expediting the time to meaningful insights.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automatic Highlights:&lt;/strong&gt; Digits’ AI-driven insights help the team prioritize their financial area of focus, turning accounting into an actionable asset. Jess highlighted the utility of seeing category shifts and vendor impacts at a glance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The automated insights are incredibly useful. They quickly tell me where I should spend my attention and focus, from high-level information like what spend categories have shifted the most, down to granular detail like significant changes in individual vendors.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Results and Impact&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The impact of Digits was both immediate and transformative for Partiful:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced Granularity: With user-friendly analytics, Partiful gained a comprehensive understanding of their financial health. &amp;quot;We&apos;re able to use our accounting as an asset rather than just a necessary task,&amp;quot; Jess praised the change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cost Savings and Operational Ease: Transitioning from costly external firms to Digits&apos; comprehensive software and service led to substantial savings and operational efficiency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Future with Digits&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking ahead, Partiful is excited by the prospect of further streamlining their financial management and looking forward to integrating Digits’ budgeting and forecasting tools into their workflows. Jess has been a Digits evangelist, spreading the word and sharing Partiful’s positive experiences with her peers. &amp;quot;During CFO roundtables, others were genuinely surprised at how Digits brought us both affordability and enhanced efficiency.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By aligning with Partiful’s innovative ethos, Digits has turned financial management from a cumbersome necessity into a streamlined, strategic advantage. Take the leap towards complete financial peace of mind with Digits. &lt;a href=&quot;https://digits.com/demo&quot;&gt;Book a demo with our team today.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>The Third Place – Cultivating Community while driving financial success with Digits</title><link>https://digits.com/customers/the-third-place/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://digits.com/customers/the-third-place/</guid><description>Discover how The Third Place transformed its financial management with Digits, turning complex bookkeeping into an efficient, proactive process, allowing focus on community growth and strategic decisions.</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 12:35:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thethirdplace.is/&quot;&gt;The Third Place&lt;/a&gt; is a software platform designed to help local businesses—like restaurants, bookshops, and art galleries—grow both their revenue and their sense of community. By enabling them to expand their offerings and forge deeper connections, The Third Place transforms these businesses into welcoming neighborhood staples where personal connections thrive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, despite its commitment to community building, The Third Place struggled with inefficient financial systems and operations. Co-founder and CEO &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/viviensin/&quot;&gt;Vivien Sin&lt;/a&gt;, had previously tried accounting solutions like Bench and Pilot but found them both costly and inaccurate. “We were too small of a startup to attract the necessary expertise, and yet the services we tried were both expensive and ineffective,” Vivien explained. Inconsistent bookkeeping not only created operational headaches but also took valuable time away from their core mission.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Search for a Solution 🔍&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pursuit of a solution led Viven to an unexpected conversation with a Digits team member at a startup dinner event. Vivien was actively seeking a new accounting platform and was immediately intrigued by Digits’ approach. “I wanted to be as hands-off as possible with basic bookkeeping — just ensure the categorization is correct and the bookkeeping takes minimal intervention,” Vivien explained.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Digits Impact 🎯&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since onboarding Digits, The Third Place has experienced a notable transformation in its financial management processes:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Streamlined Accuracy and Communication:&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digits impressed with its swift, insightful responses, vital for a hands-off approach to bookkeeping. “The response rate is phenomenal,” Vivien observed. “When feedback is provided, it’s integrated quickly and efficiently, which was unmatched in our previous experiences.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Smart, Intuitive Insights and Dashboards:&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digits’ visual dashboard became a game-changer. “It feels like Digits anticipates the questions I’m going to ask and provides the answers immediately,” Vivien said. This efficiency saves her 45 minutes every time she engages with the platform, allowing her to focus on high-level business decisions rather than bookkeeping.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;A Human Touch in Accounting:&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond its AI-powered automation, Digits sets itself apart with an exceptional customer experience. Vivien emphasized the intelligence and proactiveness of the Digits team:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;It&apos;s refreshing to engage with professionals who not only grasp our needs but proactively drive solutions with remarkable intelligence.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike past providers Bench and Pilot, where financial management felt like a frustrating chore, Digits made accounting for The Third Place seamless, personal, and supportive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vivien wholeheartedly recommends Digits to tech startups and businesses:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Digits provides a superior product with a human touch. It’s a game-changer for businesses seeking efficiency and clarity in their financial operations.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is your business ready to experience streamlined accounting with Digits? Discover how our AI-powered tools can revolutionize your financial management by &lt;a href=&quot;https://digits.com/demo/&quot;&gt;booking a demo today.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>A Seamless Transition with Digits: Achieving Financial Clarity at Particle</title><link>https://digits.com/customers/particle/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://digits.com/customers/particle/</guid><description>Discover how Particle News transformed its financial management with Digits, gaining efficiency and clarity through a unified platform that saved time and reduced costs, allowing focus on innovation and strategic growth.</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 12:06:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://particle.news/&quot;&gt;Particle News&lt;/a&gt;, an innovative AI-powered news aggregator, is on a mission to redefine how users engage with news by offering noise-free, tailored summaries from a multitude of sources. However, like many startups, Particle struggled with a fragmented and time-consuming approach to financial management, distracting them from their focus on growth and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Challenge 🧮&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before adopting Digits, Particle utilized a mix of Quickbooks Online, an external accountant &amp;amp; bookkeeper, and tools like Gusto and Carta, creating a disjointed financial ecosystem. This mix led to hefty manual workloads and a ton of inefficiencies that distracted them from their core mission. As Particle&apos;s co-founder and CEO, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/sarabeykpour/&quot;&gt;Sara Beykpour&lt;/a&gt;, reflected, &amp;quot;As a startup founder and a mom, I literally have no time.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Discovering Digits  🚀&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sara&apos;s decision to transition to Digits was influenced by a critical need for a solution that was much more streamlined – saving her valuable hours and offering a comprehensive platform that unified their financial operations. Here’s why Digits stood out:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integrated Platform:&lt;/strong&gt; Digits provided a unified system that effortlessly connected with Particle&apos;s existing finance tools, erasing the need for multiple platforms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User-Centric Design:&lt;/strong&gt; The collaborative, interactive UI of Digits allowed for more engaging financial oversight. &amp;quot;That screenshot that sparked my interest in Digits initially is something that I now love whenever there&apos;s a question. I get to interact with my team, accountants and finances directly where they are.&amp;quot; Sara noted, highlighting how the collaborative interface and tools transformed the way they interact with and discuss their finances.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time and Cost Efficiency:&lt;/strong&gt; By employing Digits&apos; flat fee structure and automation, coupled with the reduction of tools and services needed – Particle saw a huge reduction in both time required and their overall costs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proactive Insights:&lt;/strong&gt; Digits&apos; proactive monitoring ensured transparency and facilitated informed decision-making. &amp;quot;The less that I have to go in and do anything, or search for information the better,&amp;quot; Sara remarked on the newfound operational efficiency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Transformation 💅&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digit’s impact on Particle was immediate and substantial:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seamless Transition:&lt;/strong&gt; Thanks to Digits’ concierge service, Particle experienced a smooth migration, allowing them to seamlessly retire previous systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;What was awesome was I had to do very little. I invited Digits to my financial tools and that was it,&amp;quot; recalled Sara.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced Efficiency:&lt;/strong&gt; Automating bookkeeping functions yielded significant time savings. In Sara&apos;s words, &amp;quot;I&apos;m able to save hours per month—whether that&apos;s my own time or an outsourced hourly rate of someone else’s time because of Digits,&amp;quot; encapsulating the freedom and focus regained.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comprehensive Tax Management:&lt;/strong&gt; All tax-related tasks were consolidated under Digits, removing typical tax season stress. &amp;quot;It&apos;s just like a huge weight off my shoulders,&amp;quot; Sara described, appreciating the ease brought by Digits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Streamlined Reporting:&lt;/strong&gt; Centralized data collection makes investor updates straightforward and efficient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The way Digits is organized just makes everything...easier for us.&amp;quot; highlighted Sara.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digits not only optimized Particle’s financial management but also perfectly aligned with its innovative ethos, enabling strategic and efficient operations. As Particle continues to grow, Digits remains a reliable partner, ensuring complete financial clarity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;If you want an easy-to-use piece of software that looks beautiful and allows you to focus on what matters –Digits is the way to go. Whether you are a tech or AI startup or something else entirely – if you want to save time, and really trust the numbers - choose Digits&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digits has fundamentally transformed how Particle manages its finances, shifting from a burdensome task to an efficient, transparent, and value-adding process. Ready to upgrade your accounting to Digits for complete peace of mind? &lt;a href=&quot;https://digits.com/demo&quot;&gt;Book a demo with our team today.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Effortless Financial Clarity: Blaide’s Success with Digits</title><link>https://digits.com/customers/blaide/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://digits.com/customers/blaide/</guid><description>Discover how Blaide revolutionized its financial clarity with Digits. Digits is an AI-powered accounting solution saved time, reduced costs, and ensured compliance, transforming tedious tasks into a seamless, integrated process. Read more on Blaide’s success with Digits.</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Blaide is a software company at the forefront of the residential construction industry. They provide AI tools for contractors to streamline their operations, relieving them from tedious back-office tasks and allowing them to concentrate on delivering exceptional hands-on service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What to Avoid&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a founder of multiple startups, Blaide’s co-founder and CEO, Michael Ducker, understood the importance of getting his accounting right to avoid the financial missteps he had experienced firsthand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He had been burned by using various systems for different financial tasks—one for bookkeeping, another for forecasting—resulting in a disorganized and fragmented financial stack. Additionally, the lack of tools with seamless integrations led to significant inefficiencies and wasted time. These issues made accounting feel like a chore, characterized by tedious manual entries and constant back-and-forth communication with a hired bookkeeper, adding no real value to the business.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Blaide, Michael wanted a comprehensive, integrated, and user-friendly accounting solution that would eliminate these manual tasks, integrate flawlessly across platforms, and provide a single source of truth for the company&apos;s financial records.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why Digits?&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael set out to find a solution that not only maintained compliance but also provided a true understanding of the company’s finances so they could make decisions based on up-to-date information. Enter Digits, which revolutionized Blaide&apos;s accounting practices by offering a one-stop solution that integrated seamlessly with their existing financial tools:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unified and Integrated System&lt;/strong&gt;: Digits’ integration with Mercury, Blaide’s primary banking platform, streamlined their financial operations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost-Effectiveness&lt;/strong&gt;: Compared to alternatives, Digits provided equivalent services at half the cost, making it a financially savvy choice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time Efficiency&lt;/strong&gt;: By automating and managing accounting tasks, Digits freed up the team&apos;s time, allowing them to focus on strategic growth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accuracy and Transparency&lt;/strong&gt;: Monthly Digits reports ensured precise tracking of financial health, fostering complete transparency and compliance with regulatory standards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Efficiencies Gained Since Adopting&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blaide has seen immediate gains since implementing Digits—it’s not just an accounting tool but a partner in growth:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Streamlined Processes&lt;/strong&gt;: Tedious, manual accounting tasks were entirely offloaded, providing Michael and his team with more time to focus on business growth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Role in Investor Communication&lt;/strong&gt;: The reliability and accuracy of monthly Digits reports significantly enhanced investor updates, ensuring stakeholders received a true and fair view of Blaide&apos;s financial status.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced Transparency&lt;/strong&gt;: Digits provided deep insights into various financial elements, including fees and prepayments, offering a stable and accurate view of Blaide’s monthly financials that go beyond the cashflow analysis most early stage founders rely on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personalization&lt;/strong&gt;: Blaide’s dedicated Digits accountant tailored a custom chart of accounts to fit their specific business model, ensuring all unique needs were met.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Human Touch&lt;/strong&gt;: The onboarding was enhanced along with one-on-one setup conversations that addressed every requirement and concern.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User-Friendly Design&lt;/strong&gt;: Digits’ intuitive interface, enriched by its aesthetic design, made financial management not just seamless but also enjoyable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t spend time on this and I love that I don&apos;t spend time on it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Digits has fundamentally transformed how Blaide manages its finances, turning what was once a burdensome task into an efficient, transparent, and value-adding process. Ready to upgrade your accounting to Digits for complete peace of mind? Book a demo with our team today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want an easy-to-use piece of software that looks beautiful and allows you to focus on what matters, Digits is the way to go.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>After 15 emails, a fintech founder had enough—here’s why he switched to Digits</title><link>https://digits.com/customers/mural/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://digits.com/customers/mural/</guid><description>Discover why Mural, a fintech startup, switched to Digits after struggling with manual accounting processes. Learn how Digits simplifies financial collaboration and delivers real-time insights for growth.</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Mural is a cross-border payments and invoicing company that uses blockchain technology to move money instantly at a fraction of the cost. Pre-Digits, Mural was using QuickBooks with a traditional accounting firm that worked to close the books by emailing back and forth. This process felt slow and manual to Mural’s CEO and Co-Founder, Sinclair Toffa. We were excited to help Sinclair simplify collaboration and spend less time managing his finances.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{% roundedBox %}&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Digits Impact TL;DR:&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frees up mental space to focus on growth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simplify collaboration with accounting team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete picture of all financial transactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{% endroundedBox %}&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The problem: Collaborating on accounting is a struggle&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a fintech, Mural has many different bank accounts. Because of this, getting the complete picture of what’s happening with the business requires a lot of manual work. From exporting data via different sources, to sharing data in varying ways, the process was time intensive and tedious.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Sinclair&apos;s biggest pain point was collaboration with his bookkeepers. Every month, he would receive emails from them with little screenshots of transactions that they couldn’t reconcile. Sinclair would reply with feedback, but the process was slow and sometimes he never heard back. After hearing about Digits several times through his founder network, Sinclair decided to finally make the switch after a 15 email long chain chasing down a couple of transactions went unresolved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The solution: Digits AI-powered accounting&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finance teams often don’t get the same attention when it comes to flashy, productivity-boosting tools as sales and marketing teams do. This can make it challenging for finance professionals to streamline their processes and maximize their productivity, even though their work is just as critical to the success of a business.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sinclair looked at some tools here and there and spoke with smaller accounting firms that approached Mural. What drew Sinclair to Digits was the simplicity of its interface and user experience. When the accounting team needs his input on specific transactions, Sinclair would receive a tag notification. He could then jump into the platform, promptly respond, and view the complete history of their collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like Digits has done a great job of having all of that out of the box for me. So, you know, it runs on an autopilot, and that&apos;s been an absolute life saver.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since joining Digits, Sinclair has seen improvements to product every month. There’s a spend analysis feature that tells him where Mural can save money and an Ask Digits GPT advisor that answers questions on demand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working on Digits has made a night and day difference us. I’m really glad I made the choice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Digits has empowered Mural with the tools and insights needed to navigate its finances in minutes. Ready to upgrade your accounting to Digits for complete peace of mind? Book a demo with our team today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>